{"test_questions": [[{"question": "The complex of RNA polymerase, DNA template and new RNA transcript is called", "opta": "transcription bubble", "optb": "replication bubble", "optc": "a translation bubble", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "RNA polymerase in prokaryotes has a removable", "opta": "alpha subunit", "optb": "beta subunit", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "sigma subunit", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Promoters for tRNAs are located", "opta": "upstream from the start codon", "optb": "downstream from the start codon", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The binding of lac repressor to DNA could be considered to be analogous to", "opta": "competitive inhibition of an enzyme", "optb": "mixed-type inhibition of an enzyme", "optc": "uncompetitive inhibition of an enzyme", "optd": "allosteric effects in enzyme regulation", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Rho-dependent termination of transcription in E. coli", "opta": "requires ATP", "optb": "requires about 50 nucleotides of uncomplexed mRNA", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "removes mRNA and holoenzyme from the DNA", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Enhancers are regions that", "opta": "bind RNA polymerase", "optb": "are adjacent to the TATA box", "optc": "are CAT box binding proteins", "optd": "modulate transcription", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Transcription by E. coli polymerase occurs in", "opta": "four phases known as initiation, propagation, elongation and termination", "optb": "three phases known as initiation, elongation and termination", "optc": "two phases known as initiation and termination", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is necessary for transcription to occur?", "opta": "DNA molecule", "optb": "RNA polymerase", "optc": "DNA polymerase", "optd": "Both DNA & RNA polymerase", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Multiple copies of 5S genes, located at a chromosomal site distinct from the other rRNA genes", "opta": "are transcribed by rRNA polymerase III and the 5S rRNA", "optb": "are transcribed by rRNA polymerase II", "optc": "are transcribed by rRNA polymerase I and the 5S rRNA", "optd": "are transcribed by DNA polymerase I", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Each tRNA molecule has a cloverleaf secondary structure consisting of", "opta": "three stem loops", "optb": "two stem loops", "optc": "four stem loops", "optd": "either (a) or (b)", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is a promoter?", "opta": "A specific sequence of DNA to which a catabolic repressor binds", "optb": "A specific sequence of DNA to which RNA polymerase binds", "optc": "A specific DNA sequence to which a restriction endonuclease binds", "optd": "None of the above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The function of the sigma factor of RNA polymerase is to", "opta": "assure that transcription begins at the proper point", "optb": "assure that transcription ends at the proper point", "optc": "assure that translation begins at the proper point", "optd": "assure that translation ends at the proper point", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In both eukaryotes and prokaryotes, a promoter region that is rich in AT bases is called as", "opta": "CATT", "optb": "Shine Dalgarno region", "optc": "TATA box", "optd": "SV40 region", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The RNA polymerases that transcribe bacterial DNA are", "opta": "multisubunit enzymes", "optb": "only active inside the cell", "optc": "interchangable with DNA polymerases", "optd": "highly glycosylated in their active forms", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Immediately after transcription", "opta": "a methylated guanine cap is added to the 51 end of the transcript", "optb": "a methylated guanine cap is added to the 31 end of the transcript", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "a poly adenylation signal is added", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Transcription factors are", "opta": "promoters", "optb": "proteins which bind to DNA and regulate transcription", "optc": "TATA boxes", "optd": "CATT boxes", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The major function of RNA polymerase's sigma factor is", "opta": "recognition of the translational stop sequence", "optb": "recognition of the transcriptional start sequence", "optc": "recognition of the transcriptional stop sequence", "optd": "recognition of the translational start sequence", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Most transcripts of protein coding genes are cleaved", "opta": "at the 3' end just after a poly adenylation signal", "optb": "at the 3' end just before a poly adenylation signal", "optc": "at the 5' end immediately after a poly adenylation signal", "optd": "at the 5' end immediately before a poly adenylation signal", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "RNA is synthesized on a DNA template in a process called __________ , which utilizes the enzyme __________", "opta": "translation, RNA polymerase", "optb": "transcription, DNA polymerase", "optc": "transcription, RNA polymerase", "optd": "replication, DNA polymerase", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The closed complex at bacterial promoters is", "opta": "in equilibrium with free RNA polymerase and the promoter", "optb": "not affected by promoter mutations", "optc": "bound more tightly when repressors are present", "optd": "not affected by activator proteins", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Transcription begins", "opta": "at the start codon", "optb": "upstream from the start codon", "optc": "downstream from the start codon", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Transcription results in", "opta": "an amino acid chain", "optb": "messenger RNA", "optc": "complementary DNA", "optd": "Okazaki fragments", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "RNA polymerase holoenzyme initiates transcription which involves", "opta": "recognition of the -10 sequence and -35 sequence", "optb": "recognition of the -10 sequence only", "optc": "recognition of the -35 sequence only", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The transcriptional regulatory proteins in eukaryotes which induce transcription usually have", "opta": "at least two distinct domains of protein structure, a DNA binding domain and an activation domain", "optb": "at least two distinct domains of protein structure and a DNA binding domain", "optc": "at least one distinct domains of protein structure, a DNA binding domain and an activation domain", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In prokaryotes, transcription is", "opta": "terminated by the stop codon", "optb": "terminated by a protein called rho", "optc": "terminated by a poly A sequence", "optd": "terminated by a start codon", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In eukaryotes, there are three different RNA polymerases. The RNA polymerase responsible for transcription of mRNA is", "opta": "RNA polymerase I", "optb": "RNA polymerase II", "optc": "RNA polymerase III", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The nucleons of eukaryotic cell has", "opta": "RNA polymerase I", "optb": "RNA polymerase II", "optc": "RNA polymerase III", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Upstream regions which are essential for correct transcription are called", "opta": "enhancers", "optb": "start codons", "optc": "promoters", "optd": "transcription factors", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Transcription of each set of rRNA genes by RNA polymerasel produces", "opta": "a single 45S rRNA precursor molecule", "optb": "a single 5S rRNA precursor molecule", "optc": "a single 18S rRNA precursor molecule", "optd": "a single 28S rRNA precursor molecule", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The regions of a gene located at -10 and -35, with respect to the start of transcription, are termed", "opta": "start codons.", "optb": "oriC regions.", "optc": "Shine Dalgarno sequences.", "optd": "promoters.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following conditions would cause the release of the lac repressor protein from the lac operator site on DNA?", "opta": "Presence of glucose in the growth media", "optb": "Presence of lactose in the growth media", "optc": "Presence of IPTG (isopropyl thiogalactoside) in the growth media", "optd": "Both (b) and (c)", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}